## **Madeline Wright**

UX and product designer

#### Profile

Product designer passionate about developing highly performant digital products while bridging the gap between users, dev team, and key stakeholders in environments ranging from start-up to global enterprise. My experience also includes front-end development, web design, UX research, and product ownership.

## Employment History

# UX design consultant (Design system & B2B) at Micron Technology, Inc. (contract), Remote

July 2023 — Present

Global leader in innovative memory and storage solutions, providing DRAM, NAND, NOR, memory cards and SSDs.

- Partnered with web and creative teams to build and formally implement
  a global design system and accompanying UI component library in AEM.
- Wrote UX and accessibility guidelines as part of the new design system and integrated it into AEM for content author and designer access.
- Currently designing all phases of UX mock-ups for web implementation on projects including Micron University and Generative AI.
- Conducted UX research and analysis to explore and improve upon product designs and to stay abreast of best practices and industry changes.
- Figma, Adobe XD, AEM, Adobe analytics, Jira, Workfront, Adobe CS, Agile

## Digital experience lead (D2C & E-commerce) at Micron Commercial Products Group, Boise, ID

March 2019 — February 2023

- Worked closely with Digital Marketing director to build a team of dedicated UX designers and front-end developers. I also helped onboard and served as mentor and coach for new team-members.
- As part of a company-wide initiative to strengthen E-commerce and brand presence on crucial.com, I led the UX strategy – working closely with SEO, product, and brand managers to re-structure the site navigation and shopping experience. The improvements resulted in 30% increase of task completion and notably reduced bounce rates on multiple pages.
- UX lead for tools optimization initiative that resulted in an overhaul of the branded product finder tools.
- Figma, Miro, UserTesting.com, AEM, Adobe Analytics, Adobe Test, Adobe Photoshop, Jira, Agile

### **UX specialist at Micron Commercial Products Group, Boise**

March 2019 — February 2021

Micron's commercial brand, Crucial offers a wide range of memory and storage products worldwide.

- Created wireframes and high-fidelity mock-ups of all re-designed crucial.com pages as the sole UI/UX designer, which improved brand presence and E-commerce presence.
- Conducted rapid user research using various research tools, specifically Usertesting.com and Baymard Institute. Utilized Usertesting.com to identify user pain points by conducting interviews and by analyzing user

#### **Details**

Boise (willing to relocate), United States, 2089170543 maddi.chapman@gmail.com

#### Links

LinkedIn profile
Portfolio website

#### **Skills**

Figma

Adobe XD

User Research

Adobe Analytics

UI/UX Wireframe Creation

Design systems

Requirements Gathering

Product Life Cycle

Adobe Target

usertesting.com

HTML & CSS

## **Hobbies**

Painting, illustrating, home gardening, travel, pets, museums, design, biking and hiking

- session replays along with the click, hover, and engagement rates across entire pages. Presentation of the results effectively resulted in crossfunctional buy-in to page optimization initiative.
- Performed internal website audit to identify ways to optimize the system scanner, cart/checkout, and solutions pages and followed through with ideation and cross-functional user journey workshops.
- Ensured designs were accessible for all users and ready for multiple language support.
- Close collaboration with local and offshore development teams to scope UX requirements and provide ongoing support and feedback.
- UXPin, XD, Usertesting.com, LucidCharts, Confluence, Jira, Agile, AEM

### Web designer at Blossom, Boise, ID

May 2017 — May 2019

Digital banking solutions for credit unions to change the way people experience money.

- Responsible for creating and presenting Credit union website wireframes based on client requests.
- Responsible for front-end build of approved designs using Bootstrap, CSS, and occasionally JS – led to 25+ successful website launches with positive client reviews on the customer experience.
- Frequent collaboration with CU clients to gather business requirements for new websites and website updates, including kick-off, progress checkins, wireframe presentation, and pos-launch reviews.
- Led an web-accessibility improvement initiative for all client websites, improving UI, flow, and code to better suit a broader range of customers.
- Helped prepare campaign graphics using Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator.
- Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Adobe CS, JS

Intern, Website and product design at Stemfinity, Inc., Boise, ID

December 2014 — December 2016

Clinical supervisor at Lilypad, LLC, Nampa, ID

January 2014 — May 2017

## Education

Bachelor of Applied Science in Web Development, Lewis-Clark State College, Lewiston, ID

Bachelor of Arts in Graphic Design, University of Idaho, Moscow, ID

#### Courses

**UX certification, Nielson Norman Group** 

April 2022 — April 2022

Improve your UX design skills, LinkedIn Learning

March 2023 — April 2023

**Certified Scrum Product Owner, Scrum Alliance** 

October 2021 — October 2021